The Circle of Life Continues...
The Lion King II: Simba's Pride is a family, adventure,
animation film directed by Darrell Rooney.
The circle of life continues for Simba, now fully grown and in
his rightful place as the king of Pride Rock.
Simba and Nala have given birth to a daughter, Kiara
who's as rebellious as her father was.
But Kiara drives her parents to distraction when she catches the
eye of Kovu, the son of the evil lioness, Zira.
Will Kovu steal Kiara's heart?
Simba (voice), played by Matthew Broderick.
Kiara (voice), played by Neve Campbell.
Kovu (voice), played by Jason Marsden.
Timon (voice), played by Nathan Lane.
Pumbaa (voice), played by Ernie Sabella.
Nuka (voice), played by Andy Dick.
The Lion King II: Simba's Pride, also titled as The Lion King 2: Simba's Pride, is a 1998 American
animated direct-to-video musical drama film produced by Walt Disney Video Premiere.
Directed by Darrell Rooney, it is the sequel to Disney Animation's 1994 film, The Lion King, with its plot
influenced by William Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet, and the second installment in The Lion King trilogy.
Animated by Walt Disney Animation Australia, the film centers on Simba and Nala's daughter
Kiara, who falls in love with Kovu, a lion from an exiled pride once loyal to Scar.
Separated by Simba's prejudice against the pride and a vindictive plot planned by Kovu's mother
Zira, Kiara and Kovu struggle to unite their estranged prides and be together.
Most of the original cast returned to their roles from
the first film with a few exceptions.
Rowan Atkinson, who voiced Zazu in the first film, was replaced by Edward
Hibbert for both this film and The Lion King 1½ (2004).
Jeremy Irons, who voiced Scar in the first film, was replaced by Jim
Cummings, who briefly provided his singing voice in the first film.
While not drawing the same attention as its predecessor, Simba's Pride
received generally positive reviews from critics and audiences.
The film explores themes of friendship, baby, africa, lion, cartoon.
The tone is emotional.